# **AGAPITO GARCIA**

434 Fourth Avenue, Bozeman, MT 87654 a.garcia@myemail.com (135) 531-1357

Seasoned clinical laboratory scientist with 11 years' experience analyzing specimens and developing procedures in healthcare settings. Assertive and supportive leadership style with a talent for strategic planning and deployment. Clear communicator with a proven track record for interdepartmental collaboration.

#### **EDUCATION**

## BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BIOCHEMISTRY

Montana State University, Bozeman, MT September 2004 - June 2008

#### MASTER OF SCIENCE IN BIOCHEMISTRY

University of Montana, Missoula, MT, September 2008 - June 2010

#### KEY SKILLS

- Leadership
- Student education
- Problem-solving
- Data analysis
- Collaboration

#### CERTIFICATIONS

 Montana Clinical Laboratory Scientist License, July 2010

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### LEAD CLINICAL LABORATORY SCIENTIST

Bozeman Deaconess Hospital, Bozeman, MT October 2015 - Present

- Calibrate laboratory instruments and act as an escalation point for complex issues, successfully solving 89% of problems within 3 hours
- Work collaboratively to develop new procedures and protocols, receiving a workplace award for teamwork in 2019
- Provide orientation for new hires and devise and deliver continuous employee education sessions, improving staff retention by 34% over 3 years
- Oversee laboratory procedures and interrogate results, successfully identifying and resolving 98% of anomalies in 2020

#### CLINICAL LABORATORY SCIENTIST

Bozeman Health, Bozeman, MT July 2010 - October 2015

- Maintained accurate inventories of equipment and supplies and placed replenishment orders, improving availability by 87% in 2011
- Tested and analyzed blood and urine samples and communicated results to physicians, successfully identifying 99.9% of clinically significant findings
- Directed lab assistants and acted as a student mentor, assisting with the training of up to 7 laboratory students per year
- Monitored the workload of a team of 10 assistants and set daily and weekly objectives, improving productivity by 45% over 4 years